This is a gate.
這是一扇門。
That is the Gate of Destruction.
那是破壞之門。
Is this really that?
真的是這樣嗎？
That can't be true.
這不可能是真的。
GODOU!
GODOU！
SOUMA.
SOUMA。
The original author is KEITA AMAMIYA.
原作者是天宮惠太。
This production and production is TOHO SHINSHA.
本次製作、製作的是東邦新社。
The executive producer is KIYOTAKA NINOMIYA.
執行製作人是二宮清隆。
GARO：Heir To Steel Armor.
GARO：Heir To Steel Armor。
He is WATARU KURIYAMA.
他是栗山涉。
He is ON NAKANO.
他在中野。
She is MIKO NAKAZAWA.
她就是中澤美子。
She is YUKA KUROTANI.
她是黑谷由香。
He is MASATO HAGIWARA.
他就是萩原正人。
That is HIRONOBU KAGEYAMA.
那是影山博信。
They are KENTEZ ASAKA, AKIHIRO YAMAMOTO, and SYUN NISHIME.
他們是 KENTEZ ASAKA、AKIHIRO YAMAMOTO 和 SYUN NISHIME。
The plan and producer is Tanaka Aya.
策劃及製作人是Tanaka Aya。
The producers are Higa Ichiro and SYUHEI OKABAYASHI.
製作人是Higa Ichiro和岡林修平。
The script was written by YOSHIKATSU KODAMA, and the script was assisted by YOSHIKATSU KIMURA.
劇本由YOSHIKATSU KODAMA編寫，劇本由YOSHIKATSU KIMURA協助。
The opening song is GARO：Heir To Steel Armor WITH JAM PROJECT.
片頭曲是GARO：Heir To Steel ArmorWITH JAM PROJECT。
Composed and arranged by YUKI KAJIURA.
由梶浦由紀作曲、編曲。
The music producer is SYUNJI INOUE.
音樂製作人是井上俊二。
They are YOSHICHIKA KURIYAMA and SHIHO TERADA.
他們是栗山芳親和寺田志穗。
They are cinematography, lighting, sound recording, art, editing, and VFX supervisors.
他們是攝影、燈光、錄音、美術、剪輯和視覺特效主管。
The costumes were made by YOU-KO, and the magic tools and magic swords were made by NOBORU KAWAKAMI.
服裝由YOU-KO製作，魔具和魔劍由川上升製作。
Special modeling is by AKITERU NAKATA, and HORROR design is supervised by JIRO.
特別造型由AKITERU NAKATA負責，HORROR設計由JIRO監督。
The action director is MASAKI SUGIMURA.
動作監督是杉村正樹。
The director is YOSHIKATSU KIMURA.
導演是木村芳勝。
Did MUTSUGI make us come here on purpose?
MUTSUGI是故意讓我們來這裡的嗎？
It was just a moment.
這只是一瞬間。
I saw it.
我看到了。
What is this?
這是什麼？
This is the entrance to the Gate of Destruction.
這是破壞之門的入口。
let's go.
我們走吧。
What is it for?
它是做什麼用的？
I don't understand that either.
我也不明白。
I have something to worry about.
我有事要擔心。
That was when RYUGA and SOUMA were sent flying in the beginning.
那是一開始RYUGA和SOUMA被飛飛的時候。
MUTSUGI seemed to know where SOUMA was going.
MUTSUGI似乎知道SOUMA要去哪裡。
He followed the magic circle and found them.
他順著魔法陣的方向，找到了他們。
Maybe that's the case.
也許就是這樣。
When I fought the horde of HORROR, I heard GODOU's voice.
當我與HORROR大軍戰鬥時，我聽到了GODOU的聲音。
I finally understood it.
我終於明白了。
It is the night of dawn that comes once every three years.
這是三年一次的黎明之夜。
This is the first step towards opening that path.
這是打開這條道路的第一步。
I'm going to the One-Eyed Forest.
我要去獨眼森林。
GODOU had told someone that he was going to the One-Eyed Forest.
GODOU告訴別人他要去獨眼森林。
That was 3 years ago.
那是3年前的事了。
GODOU probably came here with MUTSUGI.
GODOU大概是跟MUTSUGI一起來到這裡的吧。
What is MUTSUGI's purpose?
MUTSUGI的目的是什麼？
let us hurry.
讓我們快點吧。
SOUMA, you don't have to resist.
SOUMA，你不必反抗。
Surrender yourself to darkness.
讓自己屈服於黑暗。
why did you do this?
為什麼要這麼做？
Of course it's for justice.
當然是為了正義。
All we need is for you to undo ZANGO's armor.
我們所需要的只是讓你解開贊戈的盔甲。
My wish will come true.
我的願望將會實現。
I was finally able to come back here.
我終於能夠回到這裡了。
SOUMA.
SOUMA。
Have you ever imagined a world without HORROR?
你曾經想像過一個沒有HORROR的世界嗎？
That is when the seal on the Gate of Destruction is broken.
到那時，破壞之門的封印就會被打破。
We can create such an ideal world.
我們可以創造這樣一個理想的世界。
Grudge prevents people from becoming unhappy.
怨恨防止人們變得不快樂。
I saved a man from HORROR.
我把一個人從HORROR中救了出來。
As a makai order, I did what was expected of me.
作為makai order，我做了人們對我的期望。
But then the man took the lives of many people.
但隨後這個人奪走了許多人的生命。
You still can't forget it?
你還忘不了嗎？
I should have told you this.
我應該告訴你這一點。
You shouldn't go through it alone.
你不應該獨自經歷這一切。
But it's my fault.
但這是我的錯。
I wish I hadn't saved that guy from HORROR.
我希望我沒有把那傢伙從HORROR救出來。
The makai order's mission is simply to protect people from HORROR.
makai order的使命很簡單，就是保護人們免受HORROR。
We cannot predict that the person we helped will later commit a crime.
我們無法預測我們幫助的人後來會犯罪。
I fully understand that.
我完全理解這一點。
That's if the same thing happens again.
如果同樣的事情又發生的話。
All I can do is watch it in silence?
我只能默默看著？
Is there any point in saving a murderer?
拯救殺人犯還有意義嗎？
It's the same as how we miss out on HORROR.
這就像我們錯過HORROR一樣。
sorry.
對不起。
MUTSUGI!
MUTSUGI！
Let us believe in humans.
讓我們相信人類。
As long as you don't lose hope, a path will always open.
只要你不失去希望，道路總會敞開。
I'll look into the Gate of Destruction a little more.
我會進一步研究一下破壞之門。
The Gate of Destruction is called the oldest gate.
破壞之門被稱為最古老的大門。
That's when the gate was opened.
就在這時，大門被打開了。
The human world has become a world where HORROR is rampant.
人類世界已經成為HORROR橫行的世界。
Our ancestors made many sacrifices to seal that gate.
我們的祖先為封住那扇門做出了許多犧牲。
However, even now, this world is full of Grudge.
然而，即便是現在，這個世界仍然充滿了怨恨。
People don't change anything.
人們不會改變任何事。
That will continue forever.
這將永遠持續下去。
Can't I continue to make the world free of Grudge?
難道我就不能繼續讓世界擺脫怨恨嗎？
I tried every possible way.
我嘗試了所有可能的方法。
And then I arrived at the existence of the forbidden fruit.
然後我就知道了禁果的存在。
MUTSUGI!
MUTSUGI！
Finally I understood.
我終於明白了。
The night of dawn, which occurs once every three years, will be the first step towards opening that path.
每三年一次的黎明之夜，將是開啟這條路的第一步。
I'm going to the One-Eyed Forest.
我要去獨眼森林。
There is a stone of everlasting darkness.
有一塊永遠黑暗的石頭。
I'm going there too! no!
我也要去那裡！不！
I'll go there alone.
我一個人去那裡吧。
Why!
為什麼！
That forest is a place where you never know what will happen.
那個森林是一個你永遠不知道會發生什麼事的地方。
What will happen to this town if we both can't return?
如果我們都回不去，這個小鎮會怎麼樣？
That's right.
這是正確的。
you don't have to worry.
你不必擔心。
hang on!
不掛！
MUTSUGI!
MUTSUGI！
My knowledge will be useful in ABYSS.
我的知識在 ABYSS 中會很有用。
Let me go there with you too!
讓我也跟你一起去吧！
This is the Gate of Destruction.
這是破壞之門。
MUTSUGI!
MUTSUGI！
Move forward.
繼續前進。
Those who seek justice!
那些尋求正義的人！
When you break this seal, your deepest desires will come true.
當你打破這個封印時，你最深切的願望就會實現。
Follow your heart.
跟隨你的心。
I'm sure you know what that means.
我相信你知道這意味著什麼。
This was here!
這是這裡！
MUTSUGI!
MUTSUGI！
Anyone who eats it will be given omnipotent power.
凡是吃了它的人都會被賦予無所不能的力量。
This is the forbidden fruit.
這是禁果。
It's inside this gate.
就在這扇門裡面。
what are you saying?
你在說什麼？
We can obtain the forbidden fruit.
我們可以獲得禁果。
A world without HORROR will be realized.
一個沒有HORROR的世界將會實現。
GODOU!
GODOU！
Let us open the Gate of Destruction now!
現在就讓我們打開破壞之門吧！
Don't be stupid!
別傻了！
You know what to expect when you open the gate.
當你打開大門時，你知道會發生什麼。
That's convenient.
那很方便。
If the gate opens, I can gather people with Grudge at once.
如果門打開的話，我就能一下子把怨恨聚集起來。
what do you do after that?
之後你會做什麼？
I'll kill them.
我會殺了他們。
They are people who will eventually turn into HORROR.
他們是最終會變成HORROR的人。
I will drive them out first.
我先把他們趕出去。
What's wrong with that?
這有什麼問題嗎？
If you have the forbidden fruit, you can do it.
如果你有禁果，你就可以做到。
True peace will come.
真正的和平將會到來。
Utsugi, calm down.
宇津吉，冷靜點。
You are strange now.
你現在很奇怪。
It's you who's weird.
奇怪的是你。
MUTSUGI! Wait!
MUTSUGI！等待！
I won't let you have your way.
我不會讓你為所欲為。
Zansae!
贊薩！
MUTSUGI! Stop it!
MUTSUGI！停下來！
Don't get in my way!
別妨礙我！
GODOU, the seal on the Gate of Destruction is broken.
GODOU，破壞之門的封印被解除了。
It will finally come true.
它最終會實現。
GODOU, what are you going to do?
GODOU，你要做什麼？
That's natural.
那是自然的。
Please return the armor.
請歸還鎧甲。
At this rate, you will be eaten by the armor.
照這樣下去，你就會被鎧甲吃掉。
Even if this body perishes, I must prevent this opening.
就算這個身體滅亡，我也必須阻止這個開口。
GODOU, the seal on the Gate of Destruction is broken.
GODOU，破壞之門的封印被解除了。
Finally it will happen.
最終它會發生。
GODOU, what are you going to do?
GODOU，你要做什麼？
That's natural.
那是自然的。
Please return the armor.
請歸還鎧甲。
At this rate, you will be eaten by the armor.
照這樣下去，你就會被鎧甲吃掉。
Even if this body perishes, I must prevent this opening.
就算這個身體滅亡，我也必須阻止這個開口。
GODOU!
GODOU！
ZANGO's armor quickly absorbed the evil energy of the Gate of Destruction.
贊戈的盔甲很快就吸收了破壞之門的邪惡能量。
The armor descended, still holding the gate.
鎧甲落下，仍然堅守著大門。
This was three years ago.
這是三年前的事了。
GODOU, did this happen because of you?
GODOU，這一切都是因為你嗎？
I didn't expect it to turn out like this.
我沒想到事情會變成這樣。
But that was unavoidable.
但這是不可避免的。
Because GODOU rejected a peaceful world.
因為GODOU拒絕了和平的世界。
Do not be silly!
別傻了！
I want you to make a different decision than GODOU.
我希望你做出與GODOU不同的決定。
It also means making your wishes come true.
這也意味著實現您的願望。
what is your wish?
你有什麼心願？
Is it to protect people by wearing the same ZANGO armor as GODOU?
穿著和GODOU一樣的ZANGO鎧甲是為了保護人嗎？
Do you want to be recognized by GODOU?
你想得到GODOU的認可嗎？
If we open the seal on the Gate of Destruction, we can protect many people.
如果我們打開破壞之門的封印，我們就可以保護很多人。
If that happens, GODOU will definitely recognize you.
那樣的話，GODOU一定會認出你的。
shut up!
住口！
SOUMA, undo your armor!
SOUMA，解開你的鎧甲！
Prove your strength now!
現在就證明你的實力吧！
Inherit ZANGO's armor!
繼承ZANGO的鎧甲！
Follow your wishes obediently.
乖乖地按照你的意願去做吧。
SOUMA, are you okay?
SOUMA，你還好嗎？
why did you come here?
為什麼來這裡？
I was able to follow in his footsteps.
我能夠跟隨他的腳步。
What did you do to SOUMA?
你對SOUMA做了什麼？
SOUMA!
SOUMA！
I will take off my armor to protect the world.
我會脫下鎧甲來保護世界。
The role of RYUGA DOGAI is played by WATARU KURIYAMA.
道外RYUGA一角由栗山涉飾演。
ON NAKANO will play the role of SHIRAHANE SOUMA, and MIKO NAKAZAWA will play the role of KOYORI.
中野溫將飾演SHIRAHANESOUMA，中澤美子將飾演小陽。
The role of the seducer is SARA OSHINO.
誘惑者的角色是忍野薩拉。
The role of Light Slash Knight ZANGO is played by YUGO FUJII.
光斬騎士ZANGO由藤井佑吾飾演。
The role of IRVA is played by YUKASUZUMURAD.
IRVA的角色由YUKASUZUMURA​​D扮演。
The role of MUTSUGI is played by YUKA KUROTANI.
陸奧MUTSUGI飾演。
The role of SHIRAHANE GODOU is played by MASATO HAGIWARA.
SHIRAHANEGODOU由萩原雅人飾演。
The original author is KEITA AMAMIYA.
原作者是天宮惠太。
The executive producer is KIYOTAKA NINOMIYA.
執行製作人是二宮清隆。
The plan and producer is Tanaka Aya.
策劃及製作人是Tanaka Aya。
The producers are Higa Ichiro and SYUHEI OKABAYASHI.
製作人是Higa Ichiro和岡林修平。
Assistant producers are KENTA YAMAOKA and KENTARO KODAIRA.
助理製片是山岡健太和小平健太郎。
Casting is MASASHI YAMAGUCHI.
選角是山口正志。
They are cinematography, lighting, sound recording, art, editing, recording, and VFX supervisors.
他們是攝影、燈光、錄音、藝術、剪輯、錄音和視覺特效主管。
Edited by MAYUMI KOMORI. The assistant director is MIRA ABE.
小森真由美編輯。副導演是阿部米拉。
The person in charge of production is HIROYUKI AKUNE.
製作負責人是阿久根弘之。
The stylist is KUNIHIKO KURODA.
造型師是KUNIHIKO KURODA。
The costume design is by YOU-KO.
服裝設計由YOU-KO負責。
The magic tools and magic swords are manufactured by NOBORU KAWAKAMI.
魔具和魔劍是川上升製造的。
Special modeling is by AKITERU NAKATA, and HORROR design is supervised by JIRO.
特別造型由AKITERU NAKATA負責，HORROR設計由JIRO監督。
They are assistants in direction, cinematography, lighting, sound recording, art, and decoration.
他們是導演、攝影、燈光、錄音、美術和裝飾的助理。
The technical producer is HIROSHI INAMURA.
技術製作人是 HIROSHI INAMURA。
ETSUKO HAKAMADA was in charge of props, and TSUBASA SAKAI was in charge of decorations.
袴田悅子負責道具，酒井翼負責裝飾。
They are stylist assistants and makeup assistants.
他們是造型師助理和化妝助理。
Costume production is SHIZUKA ONDA.
服裝製作是SHIZUKA ONDA。
They are in charge of studio sales, art progress, equipment, and painting.
他們負責工作室銷售、藝術進度、設備和繪畫。
They are special modeling and HORROR costume production staff, special makeup and modeling production.
他們是特殊造型和HORROR服裝製作人員，特殊化妝和造型製作。
The action coordinator is KAZUSADA SAKUMA.
行動協調員是佐久間和田。
They are stuntmen.
他們是特技演員。
They are OMNIBUS JAPAN.
他們是 OMNIBUS JAPAN。
They are DRAWIZ.
他們是DRAWIZ。
They are D/VISUAL.
他們是D/VISUAL。
They are FINE WAVE.
他們是細波。
They are TRIPOINT and VILLARD.
他們是 TRIPOINT 和 VILLARD。
Sound design is by HIROKI KATO.
聲音設計由加藤弘樹負責。
The OP director is YOSUKE ASADA.
OP監督是淺田洋介。
The music producer is SYUNJI INOUE.
音樂製作人是井上俊二。
The ending theme song is Immortal Shura no Namida.
片尾曲是《不朽修羅之波》。
The singer is JAM PROJECT.
歌手是JAM PROJECT。
The production coordinator is NAO ARISAWA.
製作協調員是有澤奈緒。
The production desk is RINA WATANABE.
製作組是渡邊莉娜。
These are art, costume, makeup and extras subcontractors.
這些是藝術、服裝、化妝和臨時演員的分包商。
The official site is SATOSHI HOSHINO.
官方網站是星野聰。
Graphic design is by SATOSHI FUNAYAMA.
平面設計由船山聰 (SATOSHI FUNAYAMA) 負責。
Special cooperation is provided by SANSEI.
特別合作由SANSEI提供。
The production and production is TOHOKU SHINSHA.
生產製作的是東北新社。
The script was written by YOSHIKATSU KODAMA, and the script was assisted by YOSHIKATSU KIMURA.
腳本由YOSHIKATSU KODAMA編寫，腳本由YOSHIKATSU KIMURA協助。
The action director is MASAKI SUGIMURA.
動作監督是杉村正樹。
The director is YOSHIKATSU KIMURA.
導演是木村芳勝。
This story is a fiction.
這個故事是虛構的。
It is completely unrelated to any real person, organization, or incident.
與任何真實的人、組織或事件完全無關。
SOUMA, show more of your Grudge!
SOUMA，展現更多你的怨恨啊！
please! Please stop it!
請！請你停下來！
Overcome the darkness!
戰勝黑暗！
You are steel!
你是鋼鐵！